<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>randomized | Sam Harper</title>
    <link>/tags/randomized/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tags/randomized/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>randomized</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2019</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 08:11:04 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>randomized</title>
      <link>/tags/randomized/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tabora Newborn and Maternal Health Initiative</title>
      <link>/project/tamani/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 08:11:04 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/tamani/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mcgill.ca/epi-biostat-occh/arijit-nandi&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Arijit Nandi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://ihi.or.tz/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ifakara Health Institute&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://care.ca/tamani&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CARE Canada&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are monitoring and evaluating a health systems strengthening program being implemented by CARE Canada, in partnership with the Society of Obstetricians and Gynaecologists of Canada (SOGC) and the Canadian Society for International Health (CSIH), in the Tabora region of Tanzania. The aim of this program is to reduce maternal and newborn mortality and morbidity by improving the availability of quality maternal and newborn healthcare services. Activities include: training and mentoring of Regional and District Council Health Management Teams (R/CHMTs) in data management and usage, supply chain management, budgeting and leadership; development of an emergency transportation system; refurbishing health centre and hospital maternity wards and procuring Basic Emergency Obstetric and Newborn CARE (BEmONC) and Comprehensive Emergency Obstetric and Newborn CARE (CEmONC) equipment; training and mentoring of health care workers (HCWs) on BEmONC, CEmONC and family planning;  and training and support of Community Health Workers (CHWs) to deliver quality maternal and newborn health education and promote utilization of health care services. We will be assessing the program’s impacts by integrating monitoring and evaluation with the delivery of interventions using a randomized phase-in or “stepped wedge” design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Funding: Global Affairs Canada&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Affordable Daycare To Empower Indian Women</title>
      <link>/project/u2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 15:12:54 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/u2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mcgill.ca/epi-biostat-occh/arijit-nandi&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Arijit Nandi&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are structural barriers to women’s empowerment in India. Among these barriers is the lack of affordable and reliable day-care services. The responsibility of providing childcare is imposed primarily on women and contributes to gender inequalities experienced by women over the life-course. The provision of affordable and reliable day-care services is a potentially important policy lever for empowering Indian women. Access to day-care might reduce barriers to labor force entry and generate economic opportunities for women. However, empirical evidence concerning the effects of day-care programs in low-and-middle-income countries is scarce. We propose a cluster-randomized impact evaluation for estimating the effect of a community-based day-care program on empowerment, economic opportunity, and health among mothers living in rural Rajasthan, India. This interdisciplinary research initiative will address an important research gap and has the potential to inform policies for improving the day-care system in India in ways that promote inclusive economic growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The video below provides some additional details about the project and some essential context for where this work is being done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;700&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/EhG45a8WUxc&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;autoplay; encrypted-media&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
