<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>maternal/child health | Sam Harper</title>
    <link>/tags/maternal/child-health/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tags/maternal/child-health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>maternal/child health</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2019</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 08:11:04 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>maternal/child health</title>
      <link>/tags/maternal/child-health/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tabora Newborn and Maternal Health Initiative</title>
      <link>/project/tamani/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 08:11:04 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/tamani/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mcgill.ca/epi-biostat-occh/arijit-nandi&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Arijit Nandi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://ihi.or.tz/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ifakara Health Institute&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://care.ca/tamani&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CARE Canada&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are monitoring and evaluating a health systems strengthening program being implemented by CARE Canada, in partnership with the Society of Obstetricians and Gynaecologists of Canada (SOGC) and the Canadian Society for International Health (CSIH), in the Tabora region of Tanzania. The aim of this program is to reduce maternal and newborn mortality and morbidity by improving the availability of quality maternal and newborn healthcare services. Activities include: training and mentoring of Regional and District Council Health Management Teams (R/CHMTs) in data management and usage, supply chain management, budgeting and leadership; development of an emergency transportation system; refurbishing health centre and hospital maternity wards and procuring Basic Emergency Obstetric and Newborn CARE (BEmONC) and Comprehensive Emergency Obstetric and Newborn CARE (CEmONC) equipment; training and mentoring of health care workers (HCWs) on BEmONC, CEmONC and family planning;  and training and support of Community Health Workers (CHWs) to deliver quality maternal and newborn health education and promote utilization of health care services. We will be assessing the program’s impacts by integrating monitoring and evaluation with the delivery of interventions using a randomized phase-in or “stepped wedge” design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Funding: Global Affairs Canada&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
